这里我们在MATLAB桌面环境中。我已将工作目录设置为该文件夹
Here we are inside the MATLAB desktop environment. I have set the working directory to the folder
包含那些假日快照。所以我们要做的是加载图像
that contains those holiday snaps. So what we are going to do is load the image
我们只是看着MATLAB工作区。我需要将这些数据放入工作空间变量中
we were just looking at into the MATLAB workspace. I need to put that data into a workspace variable
叫我。这是我个人的形象短手。我们使用iread功能。
called im. That is kind of my personal short hand for image. We use the iread function.
图像读取的简称。我们输入了包含该文件的相当神秘的文件名
Short for image read. And we put in the rather cryptic name of the file that contains the
图片。因此我们将图片加载到名为im的工作空间变量中。另一个
image. And we therefore load the picture into this workspace variable called im. Another
工具箱功能允许我们将变量显示为图像。
toolbox function allows us to display a variable as an image.
在这里我们可以看到它;在这里，我们可以看到从MATLAB内部显示的鳄鱼
And here we can see it; here we can see the crocodile displayed from inside the MATLAB
环境。图像文件不仅包含我们正在查看的像素信息
environment. The image file contains not just the pixel information that we are looking
在这儿;它还包含我们称之为元数据的内容。那么让我们回去看看我们是否
at here; it also contains what we call the metadata. So let’s go back and see if we
可以找到元数据。我们将关闭该图像，我们将修改我们的阅读命令
can find the metadata. We will close that image and we will modify our reading command
这样它就会返回两个输出变量。变量im和the中的像素数据
so that it returns two output variables. The pixel data in the variable im and the
元数据到另一个名为meta的变量。我们走了。并显示该变量
metadata into another variable called meta. There we go. And display that variable called
元。我们可以在这里看到有关图像的有趣信息，我们可以看到日期
meta. And we can see interesting information here about the image, we can see the date
它被拍摄，我们可以看到它是用松下相机拍摄的，我们可以看到
that it was taken, we can see that it was taken with a Panasonic camera and we can see
相机的模型。该子结构中有更多详细信息。
the model of the camera. There is even more detail information in this sub-structure.
在这里我们可以看到曝光时间和相机的F值
And here we can see the exposure time and the F number of the camera when I took that
特别的图片，我们可以看到闪光灯没有发射和许多其他信息
particular picture and we can see that the flash didn’t fire and lots of other information
同样。但是，我们正在超越自我
as well. But we are getting ahead of ourselves, we
一直在处理彩色图像和颜色是我们不会去的主题
have been dealing with a colour image and colour is a topic that we are not going to
再访问​​几周。所以让我们从更简单的事情开始吧。
visit for another couple of weeks. So let’s start with something a little bit simpler.
我们将看一些人称之为黑白图像，但更重要的是
We are going to look at what some people call a black and white image, but what is more
正确地称为灰度图像。所以我在这里要做的就是清除所有
correctly known as a greyscale image. So what I am going to do here is to clear all the
工作区中的变量，我将清除控制台。我要加载
variables in the workspace, I am going to clear the console. And I am going to load
一个新的图像，这是一个随软件一起提供的图像，它是一个街道的图像
a new image and this is an image that is shipped with the software, it is an image of a street
在巴黎及其文件中有PNG的扩展，代表便携式网络图形。
in Paris and its file has got an extension of PNG which stands for portable network graphic.
它只是另一种图像文件格式。将其加载到工作空间中的变量中
It’s just another type of image file format. Load that into the workspace into the variable
IM。现在我们可以在这里看到有关变量的信息。它说它是851
im. Now we can see over here the information about the variable. It says that it is 851
行数1280列。MATLAB将此视为矩阵。有一些有趣的
rows by 1280 columns. MATLAB is considering this as a matrix. There is a few interesting
关于这个矩阵的事情。MATLAB提供了检查矩阵元素的工具。
things about this matrix. MATLAB provides a facility to examine the elements of a matrix.
我们通过右键单击变量来做到这一点，让我们最大化视图。
We do that by right clicking on the variable, and let’s maximise the view.
在这里，我们可以看到这个中所有数字的一个小的子部分，
And here we can see a small, sub-section of all the numbers that are within this very,
非常大的矩阵。它是一个电子表格样式显示，它有滚动条，我们可以
very large matrix. It is a spreadsheet style display, it’s got scroll bars and we can
滚下来，看到很多很多数字。你会发现它们都是整数。
roll down and see lots and lots of numbers. And you will see they’re all integer numbers.
你会看到没有负面的，你也会注意到没有
You will see that there are no negative ones and you will also notice that there are none
大于255。
bigger then 255.
另一件需要注意的是，这个变量有一个类型，那个类型是uint8和
Another thing to notice is that this variable has got a type and that type is uint8 and
这是无符号整数8位的简写或代码。所以这个变量中的所有数字
that is short hand or code for unsigned integer eight bits. So all the numbers in this variable
im是8位无符号整数，这意味着它们可以具有的最小值
im are eight bit unsigned integers, which means the smallest value they could have is
0和它们可以拥有的最大值是255。
0 and the greatest value that they can have is 255.
MATLAB变量im包含很多数字，但它们起源于图像所以数字
The MATLAB variable im contains a lot of numbers, but they originated from an image so the numerical
该变量中的信息表示视觉信息。所以让我们展示一下吧
information within that variable represents visual information. So let’s display it
作为一个图像而不是显示为数字，我们使用我们之前使用的函数，
as an image rather then display it as numbers and we use the function we used earlier, the
idisp函数。传递图像。在这里，我们看到一张巴黎街道的照片。
idisp function. Pass in the image. And here we see a picture of a Parisian street.
现在我们可以做的是我们可以检查构成该图像的各种像素。那么我们
Now what we can do is we can examine the various pixels that comprise this image. So let’s
看看这里的一个像素，如果我点击它，它会显示三个
have a look at a pixel over here and if I click on that, it displays three pieces of
信息。第一条信息是该特定像素的坐标
information. The first piece of information is the coordinate of this particular pixel
并且坐标是105-即水平坐标-和87，即
and the coordinate is a 105—that is the horizontal coordinate—and 87, which is the
垂直坐标。现在处理惯例的图像是水平坐标，
vertical coordinate. Now the image processing the convention is that the horizontal coordinate,
我通常将其称为变量u，从左到右和垂直增加
I refer to that generally as the variable u, increases from left to right and the vertical
我通常称为v的坐标从顶部到底部增加。该
coordinate which I generally refer to as v increases from the top to the bottom. The
此处显示的其他信息是所谓的灰度值。
other piece of information that is displayed here is what is called the greyscale value.
这是该特定坐标处的像素的数值，在这种情况下
That is the numeric value of the pixel at that particular coordinate and in this case
它的值为194.我们说像素值可以变化
it has a value of a 194. And we said that the pixel values can vary
在0到255之间。惯例是低数字是暗的而高数字是亮的。
between 0 and 255. Convention is that a low number is dark and a high number is bright.
255是最大值对应亮白色;0，最小值，对应
255 being the largest value corresponds to bright white; 0, the smallest value, corresponds
到了最暗的黑暗。这个特殊值-一个194-相当明亮。如果我点击一个值
to the darkest dark. This particular value—a 194—is fairly bright. If I click a value
在这个黑暗的门口，我们看到它只有12的值。看看它的阴影
in this dark doorway we see it has got a value only of 12. Look down on the shadow of the
街道，我们看到它的值为66.所以像素值反映了强度
street, we see it has got a value of 66. So the pixel values are reflecting the intensity
在场景中的这个特定点上的光。我们还可以访问此像素值
of light at this particular point in the scene. We can also get access to this pixel value
通过直接寻址矩阵内的元素。矩阵是工作空间变量
by addressing the element within the matrix directly. The matrix is the workspace variable
我和我们需要首先提供行坐标，这是653，我们需要
im and we need to provide first of all the row coordinate, which is 653, and we need
提供列坐标，即562.我们访问矩阵的那个元素
to provide the column coordinate, which is 562. We access that element of the matrix
我们看到66的灰度值。现在注意到这里发生的是那个
and we see the grayscale value of 66. Now notice what has happened here is that the
指数已被逆转。当我们索引到矩阵时，我们提供行坐标
indices have been reversed. When we index into a matrix we provide the row coordinate
首先是列坐标。通常，当我们引用图像中的坐标时
first then the column coordinate. Typically, when we refer to the coordinate in the image
我们首先编写水平坐标，然后编写垂直坐标。
itself, we write the horizontal coordinate first and then the vertical coordinate.